LOUIS : So you want me to tell you the story of my life .
INTERVIEWER : Like I said , that 's what I do . I interview people .
I 'm a collector of lives .
FM radio , KFRC .
LOUIS : You 'll need a lot of tape for my story .
No problem . I got a bag full of tape .
LOUIS : You followed me here , didn 't you ?
Yeah , I suppose I did .
You seemed very interesting .
This is where you live ?
LOUIS : No .
It 's just a room .
INTERVIEWER : What do you say we get started ?
What do you do ?
LOUIS : I 'm a vampire .
[ Chuckling ] I haven 't heard that before .
You mean this literally , I take it ?
LOUIS : Absolutely .
I was waiting for you in that alley .
Watching you watching me .
And then you began to speak .
What a lucky break for me .
LOUIS : Perhaps lucky for both of us .
INTERVIEWER : You said you were
waiting for me .
What were you going to do ? Kill me , drink my blood ?
LOUIS : Yes .
But you needn 't be concerned now .
INTERVIEWER : You really believe this , don 't you , that you 're a vampire ?
We can 't begin this way .
Let me turn on the light .
- I thought vampires didn 't like light . - We love it .
I only wanted to prepare you .
[ Loud effect when light turned on ]
Christ !
Don 't be frightened .
I want this opportunity .
INTERVIEWER : How the hell did you do that ?
LOUIS : The same as you do .
A series of simple gestures .
Only I moved too fast for you to see .
I 'm flesh and blood
but not human .
I haven 't been human for 200 years .
Please ...
How can I put you at ease ?
Shall we begin like " David Copperfield " ?
" I am born ...
" ... I grew up . "
Or shall we begin when I was born to darkness , as I call it .
LOUIS : That 's where we should start , don 't you think ?
You 're not lying , are you ?
LOUIS : Why should I lie ?
LOUIS : 1791 was the year it happened .
I was 24 .
Younger than you are now .
But times were different then . I was a man at that age .
The master of a large plantation , just south of New Orleans .
I had lost my wife in childbirth .
She and the infant had been buried less than half a year .
I would 've been happy to join them .
I couldn 't bear the pain of their loss .
I longed to be released from it .
[ Horse neighs , crickets chirp ]
[ Scattered voices , ambient bar noise ]
LOUIS : I wanted to lose it all :
my wealth
my estate
my sanity .
How many aces are in a deck ?
Are you calling me a cheat ?
GAMBLER : No , I 'm calling you a piece of stinking offal !
[ Rifle clicks ]
You lack the courage of your convictions . Do it !
LOUIS : Most of all , I longed for death .
I know that now .
I invited it .
A release from the pain of living .
[ Scattered conversations and laughter ]
LOUIS : My invitation was open to anyone .
To the whore at my side .
To the pimp that followed .
But it was a vampire that accepted .
THIEF : Give me your money or you die !
[ Screaming ]
[ Sound of neck cracking ]
[ Lestat hisses ]
[ Dramatic , high-pitched instrumental music ]
LESTAT : Do you still want death ?
Or have you tasted it enough ?
LOUIS : Enough .
LOUIS : He left me there , on the banks of the Mississippi
somewhere between life and death .
[ Coughing ]
[ Rifle clicks ]
Who are you ? What 're you doing in my house ?
LESTAT : I 've come to answer your prayers .
LESTAT : Life has no meaning anymore ... does it ?
The wine has no taste .
The food sickens you .
There seems no reason for any of it ... does there ?
What if I could give it back to you ?
Pluck out the pain
and give you another life ?
One you could never imagine .
And it would be ... for all time .
And sickness
and death
could never touch you again .
Don 't be afraid .
I 'm going to give you the choice
I
never had .
LOUIS : That morning , I was not yet a vampire
and I saw my last sunrise .
I remember it completely
and yet I can 't recall any sunrise before it .
I watched the whole magnificence of the dawn for the last time
as if it were the first .
And then I said farewell to sunlight
and set out to become
what I became .
[ Crickets chirp ]
[ Loon cries ]
LESTAT : Have you said your good-byes to the light ?
[ Louis gasps and screams ]
LESTAT : I 've drained you
to the point of death .
If I leave you here
you 'll die .
Or
you can be young always , my friend
as we are now .
But you must tell me
will you come
or no ?
LOUIS : Yes .
Yes .
[ Heavy breathing and grunting ]
[ Simulated heartbeat , background ]
[ Wailing and choking ]
LESTAT : Your body 's dying .
Pay no attention .
It happens to us all .
[ Louis gasps ]
[ Lestat sighs ]
LESTAT : Now look
with your vampire eyes .
What did you see ?
LOUIS : No words can describe it .
Might as well ask Heaven what it sees .
No human can know .
LOUIS : The statue seemed to move , but didn 't .
The world had changed , yet stayed the same .
I was a newborn vampire , weeping at the beauty of the night .
LOUIS : Perhaps you 'd like another cigarette ?
INTERVIEWER : I would . It 's not bothering you , is it ?
I don 't assume it would . It 's not like you 'll die from cancer .
I don 't think so .
INTERVIEWER : What about crucifixes ? LOUIS : Crucifixes ?
Can you look at them ?
Actually , I 'm quite fond of looking at crucifixes .
And the stake through the heart ?
LOUIS : Nonsense .
And coffins ?
Coffins .
Coffins , unfortunately , are a necessity .
LESTAT : [ Whispering ] Don 't worry .
Soon
you 'll be sleeping as soundly as you 've ever slept .
And when you awake
I 'll be waiting for you
and so will all the world .
[ Violin playing period music ]
LOUIS : Blood , I was to find , was a necessity as well .
I awoke the next evening with a hunger I had never felt .
WOMAN : Once you taste this
you 'll never go to another tavern again .
LESTAT : You think so ?
But what if I 'd rather taste your lips ?
My lips are even sweeter still .
[ Heavy breathing ]
[ Woman moans ]
My friend
should taste those lips .
WOMAN : [ Trembling ] Is his
kiss
as deep
as yours ?
LESTAT : Deeper , ma chérie .
[ Violin playing , talking and laughter , background ]
[ Heavy breathing ]
[ Louis gasps ]
I will not take her life .
I 've done it for you .
[ Panting ] She 's dead
as a doornail , my friend .
LESTAT : It 's so easy , you almost feel sorry for them .
You 'll get used to killing .
Just forget about that mortal coil .
You 'll become accustomed to it , all too quickly .
Are you not hungry ?
LESTAT : Au contraire , ma chérie .
He could eat the whole colony .
[ Lestat laughs hysterically ]
[ Yvette gasps ]
I will finish it .
LOUIS : Now leave us .
LESTAT : Can 't you pretend , you fool ?
Don 't give the game away .
We 're lucky to have such a home .
Pretend to drink , at least .
Such fine crystal shouldn 't go to waste .
LESTAT : I know .
It gets cold so quickly .
LOUIS : We can live like this ?
On animal blood ?
I wouldn 't call it living . Call it surviving .
Useful trick if you 're on a ship for a month .
There 's nothing in the world now that doesn 't hold some ...
Fascination .
Yes .
LESTAT : I 'm bored with this prattle . LOUIS : We can live without killing .
It 's possible .
Anything is possible .
But just try it for a week .
Come into New Orleans and let me show you some real sport .
[ Orchestral music plays ]
LOUIS : Lestat killed two , sometimes three a night .
A fresh young girl
was his favorite for the first of the evening .
For seconds , he preferred a gilded , beautiful youth .
But the snob in him loved to hunt in society .
The blood of the aristocrat thrilled him best of all .
The trick is not to think about it .
You see that one ?
Widow St. Clair .
LESTAT : She had that gorgeous young fop murder her husband .
LOUIS : How do you know ?
Read her thoughts .
I can 't .
The " dark gift " is different for each of us .
But one thing is true of everyone . We grow stronger as we go along .
Just take my word for it .
She blamed a slave for his murder .
LESTAT : Imagine what they did to him .
Evil-doers are easier , and they taste better .
WIDOW ST . CLAIR : Enchantée , monsieur .
Enchantée .
[ Dog barks ]
MAN : Where are we going ?
Nowhere .
Now , young man , you really amaze me !
I 'm old enough to be your grandmother .
[ Widow St. Clair moans ]
Oh , yes , that 's the melody .
I remember it .
[ Classical music plays , background ]
[ Dogs continue barking and growling ]
WIDOW ST . CLAIR : [ Screaming ] Murderer !
My little papillons !
[ Hysterical ] My butterflies , he killed them !
No ... no !
[ Cracking of neck ]
You ... whining coward of a vampire
who prowls killing rats and poodles ! You could 've finished us !
You 've condemned me to Hell !
I don 't know any Hell .
[ Louis wailing ]
LESTAT : [ Chuckling ] That 's more like it !
Anger ! Fury !
That 's why I chose you !
[ Louis groaning and wailing ]
[ Lestat chuckles ]
But you can 't kill me , Louis .
[ Louis breathes heavily ]
Feed
on what you will .
Rats , chickens
poodles .
I 'll leave you to it
and watch you come around .
LESTAT : Remember :
Life without me
would be even more
unbearable .
[ Lestat chuckles ]
[ Birds ' wings flutter ]
[ Woman screaming ]
[ Child crying ]
[ Crickets chirping ]
[ Rapid drumbeat , background ]
[ Fire roars ]
[ Chanting , drumbeat continues ]
[ Softly ] Consider yourself lucky .
In Paris , a vampire must be clever for many reasons .
Paris ?
Here all one needs is a pair of fangs .
You came from Paris ?
As did the one who made me .
Tell me about him . You must 've learned something from him .
I learned absolutely nothing .
I wasn 't given a choice , remember ?
You must know something about the meaning of it all .
[ Yelling ] Why ? Why should I know these things ?
Do you know them ?
That noise
it 's driving me mad !
We 've been here for weeks with nothing but that noise !
They know about us .
They watch us dine on empty plates and drink from empty glasses .
LESTAT : Come
to New Orleans then .
The Paris Opera 's in town . We can try some French
cuisine .
Forgive me if I have a lingering respect for life .
You 'll soon run out of chickens , Louis .
[ Dramatic , instrumental beat ]
[ Flames roar , drumbeat intensifies ]
[ Horse neighs ]
Monsieur Louis ?
YVETTE : You don 't want any supper ?
No , ma chérie .
We 're worried about you , Master .
When is it that you go riding in the field ?
And how long since you 've been to the slave quarter ?
YVETTE : Everywhere there is death .
Are you still our master at all ?
That will be all , Yvette .
YVETTE : I will not go unless you listen to me .
You must send away this friend of yours .
The slaves are all frightened of him
and they are frightened of you .
LOUIS : I 'm frightened of myself .
[ Yvette gasps ]
[ Yvette screams hysterically ]
LOUIS : Hush !
[ Smashing ]
[ Scattered voices , flames roar ]
Hear me now !
This place is cursed !
Damned !
And , yes , your master is the Devil !
LOUIS : Get out while you can ! You 're all free !
Do you hear me ?
Run !
Save yourselves !
[ Mirror shatters ]
[ Flames roar ]
Perfect ! Perfect !
Just burn the place ! Burn everything we own !
Have us living in a field , like cattle !
You thought you could have it all .
Shut up , Louis !
LESTAT : Come on !
[ Dramatic , instrumental beat , background ]
LOUIS : Where are we ?
LESTAT : Where do you think , my idiot friend ?
We 're in a nice , filthy cemetery .
Are you happy ?
LESTAT : Is this fitting ? Proper enough ?
We belong in Hell .
What if there is no Hell ?
Or they don 't want us there ? Ever think of that ?
LOUIS : But there was a Hell .
And no matter where we moved to , I was in it .
[ Thunder crackles ]
We rented rooms on the waterfront of New Orleans .
[ Women giggling ]
WOMAN : Your skin is icy .
[ Melody on piano , women giggle ]
LESTAT : Your friend has no head for wine .
[ Woman giggles ]
Don 't worry .
I can warm that cold skin of yours better than she can .
LESTAT : Do you think so ?
WOMAN : Why
you 're warm now !
But the price is high .
Your pretty friend , I exhausted her .
Soft .
So soft .
I can see you lying on a bed of satin .
Such things you say .
Do you know what manner of bed ?
[ Woman breathes heavily ]
LESTAT : Should we put out the light ?
Uh-huh .
LESTAT : And then put out the light .
[ Woman walls ]
[ Woman gasps ]
LESTAT : But once I 've put out thy light
I cannot
give it vital breath again .
Its needs must wither .
For you , Louis .
You can pretend it 's wine .
She 's not dead !
You 're in love with your mortal nature . You resist what can bring you peace .
You call this peace ?
We 're predators , whose all-seeing eyes give them detachment !
LOUIS : The girl , Lestat ! LESTAT : Take her ! End that hunger !
No !
[ Woman screaming ]
LESTAT : Now , my child .
You 're tired , you want to sleep !
[ Smashing ]
[ Woman sobbing ]
[ Thud ]
WOMAN : [ Shrieking ] It 's a coffin !
[ Wailing ] A coffin ! Let me out !
WOMAN : I 'm not dead !
It 's your coffin , enjoy it . Most of us never get to know what it feels like .
Why do you do this ?
I like to do it . I enjoy it . Take your aesthete 's taste to purer things .
Kill them swiftly if you will , but do it !
For do not doubt you are a killer , Louis !
[ Banging and screaming ]
LESTAT : What 's that ? WOMAN : It 's a coffin .
So it is . You must be dead .
I 'm not dead , am I ?
LOUIS : No . You 're not dead .
LESTAT : Not yet .
Finish this now !
LESTAT : You finish it !
WOMAN : [ Sobbing ] Save me from him !
Save me !
You 'll let me go ?
I can 't die like this !
I need a priest .
My friend is a priest . He 'll hear your sins before you die .
Unless ... I make her one of us .
No !
Then take her , Louis , end her suffering ! End yours !
[ Lestat breathes heavily ]
LESTAT : Now
are you happy ?
My God !
To think you
are all I have to learn from .
LESTAT : In the Old World
they called it the " dark gift . "
And I gave it to you .
[ Sound of sewer water running ]
[ Rat shrieks ]
MAN : Don 't go that way , Monsieur . It 's the plague .
MAN : Go back the way you came ! LOUIS : The way I came ...
[ Fast-paced , dramatic music ]
CLAUDIA : Mama .
Please help us .
Papa left us and didn 't come back .
Please , wake Mama , Monsieur .
[ Claudia cries and gasps ]
[ Lestat giggles ]
LESTAT : My philosopher . My martyr .
" Never take a human life . "
This calls for a celebration .
[ Lestat sings cheerful melody ]
LESTAT : There 's still life in the old lady yet .
Come back !
[ Shouting ] You are what you are !
Merciful death .
How you love your precious guilt .
LOUIS : Her blood coursed in my veins
sweeter than life itself .
And , as it did , Lestat 's words made sense to me .
I knew peace only when I killed .
When I heard her heart in that terrible rhythm , I knew what peace could be .
[ Sewer-water running ]
[ Louis gasps ]
LESTAT : All I need to find you , Louis , is follow the corpses of rats .
Pain is terrible for you .
You feel it like no other creature , because you 're a vampire .
You don 't want it to go on .
No .
Then do what it is in your nature to do
and you will feel as you felt with that child in your arms .
LESTAT : Evil is a point of view .
God kills indiscriminately
and so shall we .
For no creatures under God are as we are . None so like Him
as ourselves .
I have a gift for you .
Come .
Please .
LESTAT : She 's here . LOUIS : What are you saying ?
You need
more congenial than mine .
LESTAT : Remember how you wanted her ?
The taste of her ?
I thought I 'd killed her .
LESTAT : Don 't worry .
Your conscience is clear .
LESTAT : Claudia .
Listen to me .
You 're ill , my precious .
And I 'm going to give you what you need to get well .
No .
You want her to die then ?
LESTAT : That 's it . Yes .
[ Simulated heartbeat rhythm , Lestat breathes heavily ]
LESTAT : Stop !
Stop !
Enough !
[ Lestat breathes rapidly ]
I want some more .
LESTAT : Of course you want more .
[ Bells ring ]
MAID : Vous m 'avez appelée , Monsieur ?
Ah , quelle belle enfant !
LESTAT : Gently , chérie .
They 're so innocent .
They must not be made to suffer .
Good .
LESTAT : Yes .
All right , now .
Stop .
Aah ... aah ... aah !
That 's enough , chérie .
You must stop before the heart stops .
I want more .
LESTAT : I know .
But it 's best in the beginning
lest the Death takes you down with it .
You 've done very well . Look at you .
Not a drop split . Very good .
Where is Mama ?
Mama 's gone
to Heaven , chérie , like that sweet lady right there .
They all go to Heaven .
All but us .
Do you want to frighten our daughter ?
I 'm not your daughter .
Oh , yes , you are .
You 're my and Louis ' daughter now .
You see , Louis was going to leave us .
LESTAT : He was going to go away .
But now he 's not .
Now he 's going to stay
and make you happy .
Louis .
You fiend .
One happy family .
He did it to make you stay with him ?
Perhaps .
He knew me . He knew I would love her more than the waking world .
LOUIS : But there was more to it .
He lavished affection on her , there is no doubt about that .
Perhaps , in the end , he did it because he was lonely too .
SEAMSTRESS : I need more light . LESTAT : She needs more light .
SEAMSTRESS : I 'll go blind without another lamp .
LESTAT : She 'll go blind .
SEAMSTRESS : Or let me fit this child during the day .
LESTAT : Well , I am afraid , Madame , that my days are sacrosanct .
LOUIS : A little child , she was .
But also a fierce killer
now capable of the ruthless pursuit of blood with all a child 's demanding .
Let me kiss it better .
[ Seamstress gasps ]
Claudia ! Claudia !
Now
who will we get to finish your dress ? Be practical !
Remember , never in our home !
LOUIS : She slept in my coffin at first
curling her little fingers around my hair
till the day when she wanted her own coffin .
But still , whenever she awoke
she would crawl into mine .
They died fast in those days , before , she learned to play with them
to delay the moment till she had taken what she wanted .
[ Buggy rattles ]
[ Claudia cries ]
WOMAN : Why are you crying , child ?
Are you lost , my love ?
Mama !
Hush , now , don 't cry .
We 'll find her .
CLAUDIA : Mama ! WOMAN : Oh , mon chère .
[ Piano playing classical melody ]
Mind the thumb , girl . Mind the thumb . That little digit .
They 're expensive , my dear .
Maybe too expensive for a young girl like you .
Claudia ! What have we told you !
Never in the house .
Give me some room .
LOUIS : To me , she was a child .
But to Lestat , a pupil
an infant prodigy with a lust for killing like his own .
Together , they finished off whole families .
[ Piano playing classical melody ]
[ Applause ]
Wonderful , wonderful .
Now try something on a more somber note .
[ Piano playing transforms into orchestral music ]
LOUIS : Time can pass quickly for mortals when they 're happy .
With us , it was the same .
The years flew by like minutes . The city grew .
Sailboats gave way to steamships
disgorging an endless menu of magnificent strangers .
A new world had sprung up around us .
And we were all Americans now .
[ Bells ring ]
[ Fog horn blows ]
LESTAT : This filthy modern tide !
What I wouldn 't give for a drop of old-fashioned Creole blood !
LOUIS : Yankees are not to your taste ?
Their Democratic flavor doesn 't suit my palate , Louis .
[ Woman singing melody ]
Now that is pure Creole .
LESTAT : Trust Claudia to have found her .
LESTAT : What ?
Don 't you want her ?
I want to be her .
Can I ?
CLAUDIA : Be like her one day ?
More melancholy nonsense . You grow more like Louis daily !
Soon you 'll be eating rats .
Rats ? When did you eat rats , Louis ?
It was a long , long time ago .
Before you were born .
[ Louis slurps ]
LOUIS : And I don 't recommend them .
LOUIS : Thirty years had passed , yet her body remained that of an eternal child .
Her eyes alone told the story of her age , staring from under her curls
with a questioning
that would one day need an answer .
Another doll .
CLAUDIA : I have dozens , you realize .
I thought you could use one more .
CLAUDIA : Why always on this night ?
What do you mean ?
You always give me a doll on the same night of the year .
I didn 't realize .
CLAUDIA : Is this my birthday ?
You dress me like a doll .
You make my hair like a doll .
Why ?
Some of these , Claudia , are so old
tattered .
- You should throw them away . - I will , then !
Claudia !
LESTAT : What have you done ?
[ Screaming ] What you told me to do !
LOUIS : You leave a corpse here to rot ? CLAUDIA : I wanted her !
CLAUDIA : I wanted to be her ! LESTAT : She 's mad !
LESTAT : She pollutes the very house we live in !
CLAUDIA : Do you want me to be a doll forever ?
LOUIS : Don 't !
Why not ? Can 't I change
like everyone else ?
[ Claudia screaming ]
[ Shrieking ] Which one of you did it ?
Which one of you did it ?
CLAUDIA : Which one of you made me the way I am ?
What you are ?
A vampire gone insane , that pollutes its own bed !
And if I cut my hair again ?
It will grow back again .
CLAUDIA : But it wasn 't always so !
I had a mother once . And Louis , he had a wife .
He was mortal , same as she .
CLAUDIA : And so was I ! LOUIS : Claudia !
You made us what we are !
Stop her .
Did you do it to me ?
How did you do it ?
And why should I tell you ?
It 's in my power .
Why yours alone ?
Tell me how it was done !
Be glad
I made you what you are .
LESTAT : You 'd be dead now if I hadn 't .
Like that damned corpse ! Now get rid of it !
You get rid of it .
Louis , why ?
You 've got to tell me .
LOUIS : You see the old woman ?
That will never happen to you .
You will never grow old .
And you will never die .
And it means something else too , doesn 't it ?
I shall never , ever grow up .
I hate him .
Tell me how it came to be that I am this
thing .
LOUIS : For thirty years I 'd avoided that place .
Yet I found my way back there
with hardly an upward glance .
You
fed on me ?
Yes .
And he found me with you .
Then he cut his wrist and fed you from him
and you were a vampire then
and have been every night thereafter .
You both did it .
I took your life .
He gave you another one .
And here it is .
I hate you both .
[ Dramatic , instrumental beat ]
LOUIS : I walked all night .
I walked as I walked years before
when my mind swam with guilt at the thought of killing .
I thought of all the things I 'd done and couldn 't undo .
And I longed for one second 's peace .
CLAUDIA : Locked together in hatred .
But I can 't hate you , Louis .
Louis , my love .
I was mortal till you
gave me your immortal kiss .
You became my mother and my father .
And so I 'm yours forever .
But now it 's time to end it , Louis .
Now it 's time to leave him .
He will never let us go .
No .
Really ?
[ Piano playing classical music ]
What is it now ? You irritate me . Your very presence
irritates me !
Does it ?
I found someone who 'll be a vampire better than you both !
Is that supposed to frighten me ?
You 're spoiled , because you 're an only child .
You need a brother .
Or I do .
I 'm weary of you both .
I suppose we could people the world with vampires
the three of us .
Oh , not you
my little Claudia .
You 're a liar .
But you upset my plans .
What plans ?
CLAUDIA : I came to make peace with you .
Even though you 're the father of lies
I want things to be as they were .
Stop pestering me then .
I must do more than that .
I 've brought a present for you .
Then I hope it 's
a beautiful woman
with endowments you 'll never possess .
Why do you say such things ?
You haven 't fed enough .
I can tell by your color .
Come and see .
Don 't be angry with me .
When I saw them , I knew they were for you .
Drunk
on brandywine . A thimbleful .
You certainly have
outdone yourself .
I promise I 'll get rid of the bodies .
We forgive each other then ?
Yes .
[ Lestat breathes heavily ]
Absinthe ?
You 've given them absinthe ?
No .
Laudanum .
Yes .
It killed them , unfortunately .
But it keeps the blood warm .
LESTAT : You let me drink
dead blood ?
You let me
drink ...
One lesson you taught me
never drink from the dead .
Louis !
[ Gasping ] Put me in my coffin .
Put me in my coffin .
CLAUDIA : [ Screaming ] I 'll put you in your coffin !
My God !
[ Lestat gasps ]
[ Choking sounds ]
Louis
lift me up !
[ Lestat takes short breaths ]
CLAUDIA : Good night , sweet prince .
May flights of devils wing you to your rest .
Should we burn him ?
Bury him ?
What would he have liked ?
The swamp ?
[ Dramatic , instrumental music ]
[ Sound of horses galloping ]
He belongs with those reptiles .
CLAUDIA : He deserved to die .
Then perhaps so do we , every night of our lives .
He was my maker .
He gave me this life
whatever it is .
LOUIS : It shouldn 't have been this way .
CLAUDIA : I did it for us .
So we could be free .
You missed him ?
He was all I knew .
It 's as simple as that .
We were like two orphans learning to live again .
We booked a passage to Europe .
LOUIS : Over the weeks , while waiting for the boat
she studied the myths and legends of the Old World
obsessed with the search of what she called " our kind . "
[ Piano playing ]
[ Knock on door ]
[ Birds chirping ]
LOUIS : Look who we forgot .
Let 's set them free .
CLAUDIA : Yes . LOUIS : Yes .
[ Bells ring ]
It 's the carriage .
[ Bells ring again ]
[ Gasping and grunting ]
CLAUDIA : [ Screaming ] No , Louis !
[ Piano playing melancholic , classical melody ]
LESTAT : Listen , Louis
there 's life
in these old hands still .
Not quite furioso .
Moderato
cantabile , perhaps .
How could it be ?
LESTAT : Ask the alligator .
His blood helped .
Then , on a diet of the blood of snakes
toads
and all the putrid life
of the Mississippi
slowly
Lestat became something
like himself again .
Claudia ...
You 've been
a very
very
naughty little girl .
[ Banging and gasping ]
[ Claudia screams ]
[ Lestat walls , flames roar ]
[ Smashing and banging of furniture ]
[ Chaos of voices in the streets ]
[ Dramatic music intensifies , Lestat walls ]
CLAUDIA : The ship is sailing without us !
LOUIS : Though the fire seemed to spread
I stood on that deck , fearful , he would come out again
from the river like some monster , to destroy us .
And all the while I thought ...
" Lestat ...
" ... we deserve your vengeance .
" You gave me the ' dark gift ' ...
" ... and I delivered you into the hands of Death for the second time . "
Though the ship was blessedly free of rats
a strange plague nonetheless struck its passengers .
Claudia and I alone seemed immune .
We kept to ourselves
pondering the mystery of each other .
We reached the Mediterranean .
I wanted those waters to be blue ... but they were black ...
LOUIS : ... night-time waters .
And how I suffered then
straining to recall the color that in my youth I took for granted .
We searched village after village
ruin after ruin
country after country .
And always we found nothing .
I began to believe we were the only ones .
There was a strange comfort in that thought .
For what could the damned really have to say to the damned ?
You found nothing ?
Peasant rumors
superstitions about garlic
crosses
the old stake in the heart .
But one of our kind ?
Not a whisper .
There are no vampires in Transylvania ? No Count Dracula ?
Fictions , my friend .
The vulgar fictions of a demented Irishman .
LOUIS : Paris
September , 1870 .
The city I 'd always dreamed of .
I was Creole , after all , and Paris was the mother of New Orleans .
A universe whole and entire unto herself .
[ Orchestral music plays ]
LOUIS : We were alive again .
Just the two of us .
And so euphoric was I that I yielded to her every desire .
[ Footsteps ]
LOUIS : So it was
when I 'd given up the search for vampires
that a vampire found me .
[ Footsteps ]
[ Church bells ring in distance ]
[ Light , playful orchestral music ]
Buffoon !
ARMAND : Santiago !
I 've searched the world for an immortal and this is what I find !
LESTAT : Bring the petite beauty with you .
No one will harm you .
I won 't allow it .
And
remember my name :
Armand .
LOUIS : Remember what I told you .
They have different powers . They 'll read your thoughts .
[ Organ playing ]
He 's the one , that 's the vampire .
SANTIAGO : Two lovers
wandering down their violet way
whose passionate embraces , each to each
permit no meditations on decay ...
CROWD : Whoa !
... until they find themselves
within my reach !
CROWD : Whoa !
[ Santiago cackles ]
[ Applause ]
Vampires who pretend to be humans pretending to be vampires .
How avant-garde .
SANTIAGO : The monk whose soul with Heaven doth commune
and spends his days
in pious contemplation ...
[ Male voice screaming ]
... finds he will meet his Maker all too soon .
[ Crowd laughs ]
SANTIAGO : For all his prayers gets no remuneration .
The lesson endeth here
and it is this :
Each one of you , my clammy hands must touch .
SANTIAGO : Each one must bend his forehead to my kiss .
But , hark !
Methinks a mortal doth approach !
[ Girl sobbing and screaming ]
SANTIAGO : What have we here ?
What beauty by my side ?
A rose in bloom , a shrinking violet ?
[ Girl shrieks ]
Perhaps she has a mind to be my bride .
Perhaps my lesson has not ended yet !
[ Girl shrieks ]
I don 't want to die !
SANTIAGO : But Death we are and have always been .
GIRL : Someone help me !
Please !
[ Girl sobbing and wailing ]
GIRL : What have I done ? SANTIAGO : We all die !
GIRL : But I 'm young !
SANTIAGO : Death is no respecter of age ! It can come any time , any place .
SANTIAGO : Just as this flesh is pink now
so it will turn gray and wrinkle with age .
GIRL : [ Shrieking ] Let me live ! I don 't care !
Then why should you care if you die now ?
And suppose Death had a heart to love and to release you ?
To whom would he turn his passion ?
Would you choose a person from the crowd there ?
A person to suffer as you do ?
Monsieur Vampire , take me !
I adore you !
SANTIAGO : You wait your turn !
Well ...
Do you know what it means to be loved by Death ?
To become our bride ?
[ Explosion ]
[ Girl cries ]
No pain .
Monstrous .
[ Dramatic , instrumental music ]
ARMAND : We live beneath .
Let me show you .
LOUIS : Monstrous .
ARMAND : Yes .
But very beautiful .
[ Footsteps ]
ARMAND : Welcome to my home .
Try him .
[ Crowd laughs ]
Two vampires
from the New World
as all we love slowly rots
and fades away .
LOUIS : Are you the leader of this group ?
If there were a leader
I would be the one .
LOUIS : So you have the answers ? ARMAND : So you have questions ?
What are we ?
Nothing
if not vampires .
LOUIS : Who made us what we are ?
Surely you know the one who made you ?
LOUIS : Yes , but the one who made him ?
The source
of all this
evil .
I understand .
ARMAND : I saw you in the theater .
Your suffering
your sympathy for that girl .
You die
when you kill .
You feel you deserve to die and you stint on nothing .
But does that make you evil ?
Since you comprehend what you call goodness , doesn 't that make you
good ?
Then there is nothing ?
ARMAND : Perhaps .
But perhaps
this
is the only real evil left .
Then God does not exist ?
I know nothing of God .
Or the Devil .
I have never seen a vision , nor learned a secret
that would damn or save my soul .
ARMAND : As far as I know
after 400 years
I am the oldest
living vampire
in the world .
Then it 's as I always feared .
You fear too much .
So much you make me fear ...
ARMAND : The one who made you
should have told you this .
The one who left the Old World for the New ...
LOUIS : He knew nothing .
Nor did he care .
Knew ?
Come , beloved .
It 's time we were on our way .
I 'm hungry
and the city awaits .
LOUIS : The place was empty as we left .
Silent as the grave .
And as we blundered through it , again came the thought :
" I have wronged Lestat .
" I have hated him for the wrong reasons . "
SANTIAGO : How did you wrong him ?
You said a name .
LOUIS : Yes , a name I don 't care to say again .
SANTIAGO : There is but one crime
among us vampires here .
It is the crime that means death to any vampire :
To kill your own kind .
LOUIS : Do you think I 'd let them harm you ?
CLAUDIA : No , you would not .
Danger holds you to me .
Love holds you to me .
CLAUDIA : Love ? LOUIS : Love .
You would leave me for Armand if he beckoned you .
Never .
CLAUDIA : He wants you as you want him . He 's been waiting for you .
He wants you as a companion .
He bides his time there .
CLAUDIA : He finds it as dull and lifeless as we do .
Perhaps .
Do you know what his soul said to me without saying a word ?
" Let him go , " he said .
" Let him go . "
Is that what I should do ?
Let you go ?
My father
my Louis
who made me ?
It will be all right .
You really believe that ?
SANTIAGO : The soldier
on returning from the war
thinks victory has ensured him against sorrow
till Death comes by
and chops him from his horse .
[ Cannon blast ]
[ Gasping and applause of audience ]
ARMAND : I was waiting for you .
LOUIS : Listen to me .
Claudia is very dear to me .
She 's my daughter .
ARMAND : Your lover .
LOUIS : No , my beloved .
My child .
ARMAND : You say so . You 're innocent .
She 's in danger , isn 't she ?
ARMAND : She is . LOUIS : Why ?
[ Light classical music on piano , background ]
ARMAND : I could give you reasons .
Her silence .
Her youth .
It 's forbidden to make one so young
so helpless
that cannot survive on its own .
LOUIS : Then blame the one who made her .
ARMAND : Did you kill this vampire who made you both ?
Is that why you won 't say his name ?
Santiago thinks you did .
LOUIS : We want no quarrel with him . ARMAND : It 's already begun .
If you want to save her ...
- ... send her away ! - Then I leave too .
ARMAND : So soon ?
Without any of those answers you so longed for ?
You said there are none .
But you asked the wrong questions .
Do you know
how few vampires
have the stamina for immortality ?
How quickly they perish of their own will .
The world
changes .
We do not .
Therein lies the irony
that finally kills us .
I need you to make contact with this age .
Me ?
Don 't you see ?
I 'm not the spirit of any age .
I 'm at odds with everything .
I always have been .
That is the very spirit of your age .
The heart of it .
Your fall
from grace
has been the fall of a century .
But the vampires in the theater ?
ARMAND : Decadent
useless .
They can 't reflect anything .
But
you do .
You reflect
its broken heart .
A vampire
with a human soul .
An immortal with a mortal 's passion .
You
are
beautiful , my friend .
Lestat must have wept when he made you .
You knew Lestat ?
Yes .
I knew him .
Knew him well enough not to mourn his passing .
LOUIS : I felt a kind of peace at last .
I had found the teacher which Lestat could never , I knew now , have been .
I knew knowledge would never be withheld by Armand .
It would pass through him as through a pane of glass .
[ Buggy rattles ]
CLAUDIA : Madeleine
Louis is shy .
Drink .
[ Louis sighs ]
Do it .
Because I cannot do it . I haven 't the strength .
- You saw to that when you made me . - You don 't know what you ask !
I have .
[ Yelling ] You have found your new companion ! You will make me mine !
How do we seem to you ?
Do you find us beautiful ?
Magical ?
Our white skin , our fierce eyes ? Do you know the thing you will become ?
CLAUDIA : Your evil is that you cannot be evil !
And I shall suffer for it no longer !
Don 't make me do this ! I cannot !
Yet , you could do it to me .
Snatching me from my mother 's hands , like two monsters in a fairy tale .
CLAUDIA : And now you weep !
I haven 't tears enough for what you 've done to me !
[ Shouting ] You give her to me , Louis !
Do this before you leave me !
[ Claudia weeps ]
Oh , God !
CLAUDIA : I love you still !
That 's the torment of it !
Who 'll care for me , my love
my dark angel , when you are gone ?
What do you think she is , Madeleine ?
LOUIS : A doll ?
A child who cannot die .
And the child who did die ?
MADELEINE : My daughter .
[ Madeleine shrieking ]
CLAUDIA : What 's happening to her ?
She 's dying .
It happened to you too
only you were too young to remember .
But if she dies ?
It 's only mortal death .
Bear me no ill will , my love .
We are now even .
What do you mean ?
What died in that room was not that woman .
What has died is the
last breath in me
that was human .
Yes , Father .
At last we are even .
PERFORMER : It 's time for justice , little one .
[ Dramatic , fast-paced music , screaming ]
[ Eerie laughter ]
Get me Armand . He wouldn 't stand for this .
Death for the others .
For you
eternity in a box .
[ Laughter ]
SANTIAGO : Walled in a dungeon .
Your only company will be your screams .
Perhaps it will take centuries .
[ Laughter ]
[ Shouting ] Take them !
LOUIS : [ Screaming ] Armand ! Armand !
[ Louis screaming and wailing ]
[ Music continues , vampires chatter and scream ]
[ Fierce laughter , Claudia screaming ]
SANTIAGO : Pleasant dreams .
[ AII cackle ]
LOUIS : No ! No !
Help !
[ Footsteps ]
[ Distorted sound effects ]
CLAUDIA : [ Sobbing ] Wake up !
[ Madeleine and Claudia screaming and gasping , echoes ]
[ Shrieking and raging ]
LOUIS : Claudia !
[ Fast-paced , instrumental music ]
[ Louis coughs and gasps for air ]
LOUIS : Where 's Claudia ?
Claudia . I cannot help her .
LOUIS : Where 's Claudia ? ARMAND : I can 't save her !
I will only risk losing you !
ARMAND : Don 't !
[ Footsteps ]
[ Sobbing and breathing heavily ]
[ Chorale music with organ , background ]
Come , Louis .
Not here .
INTERVIEWER : So a vampire can cry ?
Once
maybe twice , in eternity .
And maybe it was to quench those tears forever that I took such revenge .
[ Dramatic , instrumental beat ]
[ Flames roar ]
WOMAN : Stop him ! It 's burning !
[ Screaming ] Get him ! Stop him !
[ Chaos and screaming ]
[ Wailing echoes ]
Aaahh !
[ Evil cackling ]
[ Screaming and cackling ]
[ Screaming ]
[ Sound of hooves pounding ]
[ Buggy rattles ]
ARMAND : Louis !
LOUIS : You didn 't even warn them , did you ?
No .
And you knew what I would do .
I knew .
I rescued you , didn 't I ?
From the terrible dawn .
You were their leader . They trusted you .
No .
You made me see their failings , Louis .
They were
doomed , stuck in their decadent time .
They had forgotten the first lesson
that we must be powerful
beautiful
and without regret .
You can teach me this ?
Yes .
To be without regret ?
Then , what a pair we could make .
But what if it 's a lesson I don 't care to learn ?
What ?
What if all I have is my suffering ?
My regret ?
ARMAND : Don 't you want to lose it ?
LOUIS : So you can have that too ?
The heart that mourns her
whom you burnt to a cinder ?
ARMAND : I swear I didn 't ...
But I know you did .
I know
you
regret nothing .
You feel
nothing .
If that 's all I have left to learn
I can do that on my own .
Louis ...
I will die .
No .
You are dead .
And you want me to quicken you once more .
And as much as your invitation might appeal to me
I must regretfully
decline .
LOUIS : For years I wandered :
Italy , Greece
all the ancient lands .
But the world was a tomb to me
a graveyard full of broken statues .
And each of those statues resembled her face .
Then , out of curiosity
boredom , who knows what
I left the Old World
and came back to my America .
And there a mechanical wonder allowed me to see the sunrise
for the first time
in 200 years .
And what sunrises !
Seen as the human eye could never see them .
Silver at first
then , as the years progressed , in tones of purple
red
and my long-lost blue .
In the spring of 1988 , I returned to New Orleans .
And as soon as I smelled the air , I knew I was home .
It was rich
almost sweet
like the fragrance of jasmine and roses around our old courtyard .
I walked the streets savoring that long-lost perfume .
[ Sirens blare ]
LOUIS : And then on Prytania Street
only blocks from the Lafayette cemetery
I caught the scent of death .
And it wasn 't coming from the graves .
The scent grew stronger as I walked .
Old death .
A scent too faint for mortals to detect .
[ Footsteps ]
[ Gate creaks ]
[ Birds ' wings flutter ]
[ Footsteps ]
LESTAT : I 'm so glad you are here !
I 've dreamed
of this moment .
She never should have been one of
us .
That 's all past , Lestat .
LESTAT : Past .
Still beautiful , Louis .
You always were the strong one .
[ Banging ]
LOUIS : Don 't be frightened .
I mean you no harm .
LESTAT : You 've come home to me then ?
You remember how I was ?
The vampire
that I was ?
Yes , I remember .
No one
could refuse me
not even you .
I tried .
LESTAT : [ Softly ] Yes , you tried .
And the more you tried
the more I wanted you .
[ Lestat sighs deeply ]
[ Helicopter pelts overhead ]
LESTAT : [ Shrieking ] I can 't bear it .
LESTAT : Such lights
and that noise !
They make the night brighter than the day .
It 's false light .
It can 't harm you .
[ Whispering ] If you stay with me , Louis
I could venture out again .
Become the old Lestat .
I must leave now .
Whatever happened to Lestat , I do not know .
I go on
night after night .
I feed on those who cross my path .
But all my passion went with her golden hair .
LOUIS : I 'm a spirit of preternatural flesh .
Detached .
Unchangeable .
Empty .
INTERVIEWER : Empty ?
That 's it ?
No , it can 't end like that .
But it has .
There 's no more to tell .
There must be more to tell . You don 't understand yourself . You 're not empty .
What I wouldn 't give to be like you , to have your power
to have seen the things you have seen .
You haven 't been listening .
I have been listening . Your story is incredible .
- It 's amazing . - Do what you want with it .
Give it to others . Learn what you can .
There 's only one way I 'll truly learn and you know it .
You brought me here for a reason .
Didn 't you ?
What reason would that be ?
You want a companion . You want a link to the outside world . That 's me .
Take me . That 's what I want .
- I refuse to let it end like this . - God , I 've failed again .
INTERVIEWER : You haven 't failed . God has nothing to do with it .
Do you like this ?
Do you like being food for the immortals ?
Do you like dying ?
[ Gasping ] Stop !
[ Heavy breathing ]
[ Tires screeching ]
[ Horns honking ]
[ Heavy breathing ]
[ Dramatic , instrumental music ]
[ Short , rapid breathing ]
LOUIS ON TAPE : 1791 was the year it happened .
I was 24 . Younger than you are now .
But times were different then . I was a man at that age .
The master of a large plantation , just south of New Orleans .
I had lost my wife in childbirth .
Someone change my shorts .
LOUIS ON TAPE : She and the infant had been buried less than half a year .
It 's good stuff .
LOUIS ON TAPE : I would 've been happy to join them .
Good stuff .
[ Gasping ]
I assume I need no introduction .
[ Gasps ]
[ Tires screech ]
[ Smashing and banging ]
I feel better already .
LOUIS ON TAPE : Most of all , I longed for death .
I invited it .
A release from the pain of living .
Ah , Louis , Louis ...
Still whining .
Heard enough ?
I 've had to listen to that for centuries .
Don 't be afraid .
I 'm going to give you the choice
I never had .